

Andrash Yang

Full-stack web developer. Former mobile app developer and indie game developer. Someone who just loves to create new things by coding and has been doing it as a job and as a hobby for more than 10 years.

Highly self-sufficient and self-motivated. Capable of designing and implementing a project from scratch and learning whatever is needed to get the job done.

Nationality: Taiwan | Language: Mandarin Chinese (native), English (fluent)

Looking for a fully remote job that values creativity.

Please visit my Portfolio Website: https://andrash.dev/

(7) in | cocoychris@gmail.com

Web Dev Skillset

- JavaScript/CSS/HTML, TypeScript, Node.js, React.js, Vite (as an alternative to webpack), jQuery, Express.js, RESTful API design, EJS (for SSR), Socket.io, Puppeteer (for web scraping) and PostgreSQL database design and operations.
- A true believer in the Object-Oriented programming paradigm, who understands its importance due to past experiences with spaghetti code.
- Familiar with non-blocking I/O, asynchronous programming, and event-driven programming.
- Familiar with unit testing using Jest and version control using Git and GitHub.
- Practices good documentation and code commenting habits. Familiar with the JSDoc documentation syntax.
- More of a library builder than a library user. Enthusiastic about building reusable libraries and components.

Other Coding Experience

- Android & iOS (non-native) mobile app development with Corona SDK (now called Solar 2D) using the Lua language.
- Indie game development with Adobe Flash (now called Adobe Animate) using the ActionScript 3.0 language.
- Side projects with the Arduino microcontroller using the C++ language.
- Programmatic 3D modeling with OpenSCAD using the OpenSCAD language for 3D printing.
- Other languages: AngelScript for game scripting.

Full-stack Projects

Playground by Andrash (My Portfolio website)

This website serves as my portfolio, showcasing my fullstack web development skills.

The site is built on a custom Multiplayer Online Game Engine, offering visitors an unconventional, game-like browsing experience.

It also includes a Map Editor, a tool that I designed to help create the playgrounds for this website. I decided to make it public so that others can also use it to create their own playgrounds.

Technologies used in the project:

React.js, Node.js, Vite, Express.js, socket.io

Automated Robot Platform (ARP) System

A web-based RPA (Robotic Process Automation) system that allows users to manage and execute automated tasks. The system can run multiple tasks simultaneously and supports a wide range of tasks including web scraping, file processing, database operations, mouse and keyboard operations, etc.

This was an internal project for a company I worked for. I proposed the idea, designed the system, and implemented the entire project from scratch.

The project was a great success and has been used by the company for more than 2 years. It has become an essential

, Jest , PM2 , TypeScript , Object-Oriented Programming style.

Most of the asset images were created by me using Inkscape.

- * Link to the website: https://andrash.dev/
- * Source code on GitHub:

https://github.com/cocoychris/andrash-portfolio

tool for automating repetitive tasks across multiple departments.

Technologies used in the project: Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API, EJS, jQuery, Puppeteer, Nut.js, PostgreSQL, MSSQL.

* Learn more:

https://andrash.dev/page/md/project_arp_system

* Demo video

https://youtu.be/IO3-2 hz4XU

Education

- Earned a Bachelor's degree in Philosophy from Chinese Culture University, graduating early with honors in 2012.
- Self-taught in programming, software engineering, game development, and web development since 2004. The first language I learned was ActionScript 2.0 (a weakly-typed language very similar to JavaScript), which I used with `Macromedia Flash MX` to make Flash games.
- First encountered OOP concepts in 2008 while migrating to ActionScript 3.0 (a strongly-typed language very similar to TypeScript). This experience made me appreciate the value of OOP in managing increasingly complex codebases, and I have been a believer in OOP ever since.

Work Experience

Information System Senior Executive

BRAND'S Suntory Ltd. Taiwan Branch 08/2019 - 02/2023

- · Working on internal web applications.
- The Automated Robot Platform (ARP)
 System mentioned above was developed during this period.

Mobile App Engineer

QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte. Ltd 01/2015 - 02/2016

- Developed mobile apps for iOS and Android using Corona SDK and Lua as the main developer.
- Developed the company's main product, a mobile app that serves as an interactive ebook reader for language learning.
- Built a library of reusable components for the company's mobile apps.
- Developed a library that supports OOP implementation including class, inheritance and type checking for Lua (since Lua is a dynamically typed language), to ensure the extensibility and maintainability as the codebase grows.

Computer Science & Coding Teacher (Part-time)

Qing Shui High School, Yilan County, Taiwan. 01/2015 - 01/2016

 Taught computer science and coding to high school students.

Mobile App Engineer Intern

QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte. Ltd 04/2012 - 02/2013

- Became familiar with Corona SDK and Lua.
- Developed mobile apps for iOS and Android using Corona SDK and Lua.

Indie game developer

09/2008 - 04/2012

- Created Flash games as a hobby and offered them for free while studying philosophy in college.
- Also worked as a freelance software developer for a few months, collaborating with my Philosophy professor to create a game-like software as teaching material for his class.